<sect1 id="installation" xreflabel="static-pages-installation">
  <title>Static Pages Installation and Use</title>
  
  <para>
    Static Pages is installed with the APM like any other package.  You
    must have the General Comments package installed and mounted to use Static
    Pages.
  </para>
  
  <sect2 id="sp-sws-setup" xreflabel="static-pages-sws-setup">
    <title>Site-wide Search Setup</title>
    
    <para>
      One of the most useful features of this package is that it allows
      static pages to be searched from the Site-wide Search package.
      To use this function:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>Install the Site-wide Search package, including support 
	  for the <computeroutput>content_revision</computeroutput> object 
	  type.</simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>Feed the
	  <filename>static-pages/sql/static-pages-sws.sql</filename> file to
	  the Oracle schema belonging to your ACS installation.</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>Try it out: scan the file system for static pages, do 
	  <computeroutput>exec sws_service.rebuild_all_index</computeroutput>
	  in <filename>sqlplus</filename> to force the index to rebuild, and 
	  visit the URL where you mounted Site-wide Search.</simpara></listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>
      Site-wide Search performance can sometimes be enhanced by the following
      procedure:
      <orderedlist>
	<listitem><para>In Oracle, build a concatenated index on
	    <computeroutput>acs_contents</computeroutput> thus:
	    <programlisting>create index acs_contents_ctnt_srchable_idx on acs_contents(content_id,searchable_p);</programlisting>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem><para>In <filename>/packages/site-wide-search/www/search.tcl</filename>, insert a hint into the database queries:
	    <programlisting>set query "select  <userinput>/*+ INDEX(acc acs_contents_ctnt_srchable_idx) */</userinput> score(1) as rank, ...</programlisting>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="sp-use" xreflabel="static-pages-overview">
    <title>A Brief Tour of Static Pages</title>

    <para>
      Suppose you've got Static Pages installed and mounted at
      <filename>/statics/</filename>.  Let's try out each of its
      functions.
    </para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
	  Put some static pages somewhere under your server's pageroot
	  (typically <filename>/web/service_name/www/</filename>).  This is 
	  where Static Pages will look for files.
	</simpara></listitem>

      <listitem><simpara>
	  Logged in as an admin, visit <filename>/statics/admin/</filename>.
	  The page will assert that "<computeroutput>There are 0 static pages 
	    in the system</computeroutput>".  This is because the filesystem 
	  has not yet been scanned.</simpara></listitem>

      <listitem><simpara>
	  Click "<computeroutput>Scan filesystem for static 
	    pages</computeroutput>".  The server will load every
	  <computeroutput>*.html</computeroutput> and 
	  <computeroutput>*.htm</computeroutput> file into the database, which
	  may take some time if there are many of them.  Perform the
	  filesystem scan again and it will resynchronize the filesystem with
	  the database, adding, updating, and removing entries from the
	  content repository as needed.
	</simpara></listitem>

      <listitem><simpara>
	  Return to the admin page and try "<computeroutput>Change
	    permissions</computeroutput>".  By default, users are allowed
	  to leave comments on any static page in the system (by following the
	  "<computeroutput>Add a Comment</computeroutput>" link at the bottom
	  of the page), and the full text of the comments will be displayed 
	  one after another at the bottom of the page.  These properties may 
	  be changed by toggling the settings displayed with each file.  Try 
	  toggling permissions and visiting the corresponding page.  You may
	  need to reload the page for your browser to flush its cache.</simpara>

	<simpara>
	  Back on the Commentability Designation page, notice that each 
	  directory is 
	  marked "<computeroutput>children commentable</computeroutput>" or
	  "<computeroutput>children not commentable</computeroutput>".  When
	  new static pages are created under the directory, they will
	  inherit this setting.  Toggling this will change the settings of all
	  descendants.  At the bottom of the page is a self-explanatory form 
	  to change the settings of all files containing a given pattern.
	</simpara></listitem>
	  
    </orderedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<!--
 Local Variables:
 sgml-parent-document: ("index.xml" "chapter" "sect1")
 End:
-->
